# **Ganan Sivagnanenthirarajah**

**Technical Product Manager** 

#### Profile

Innovative leader with 3 years of experience in software development. Recognized for creatively architecting and launching Lifion's Unified Messaging System to scale user notifications and improve client sentiment scores by 10% for 20k daily users.

## Education

Bachelor of Applied Science, Honours Electrical Engineering - Co-operative Program (BASc), University of Waterloo

September 2017 — April 2022

# Work Experience

# Technical Product Manager at Lifion by ADP, New York City $\Box$

August 2022 — September 2023

- Improved client sentiment by 10% for 20k daily active users after building, testing & releasing Lifion's Unified Messaging System to synchronize messages between internal & external applications.
- Achieved application's SOC compliance by implementing user provisioning & reporting tools for Lifion's low-code version control system (Lifion Git).
- Reduced pull request (PR) time **by 30%** after revitalizing code management tools for Lifion Git while engaging with **over 300 stakeholders**.
- Led 2 engineering teams (10 developers) & increased team velocity by effectively communicating requirements using tools like Figma & Miro while taking initiative on organizing team building social events.

# **Technical Product Owner Intern at Lifion by ADP, Remote** □

January 2021 — April 2021

- Modernized mobile search with cross-functional teams to reduce user taps from 4 to 1 by unifying search & adding ML suggestions.
- Increased release quality by 15% after designing automated tests & deploying Pendo Analytics to track user journeys.

## **Technical Product Owner Intern at Lifion by ADP, Remote** □

June 2020 — September 2020

- Slashed configuration time by 90% after redesigning UI & releasing features like cURL support & Swagger Docs for connecting outbound REST configurations in Lifion's low code platform.
- Prioritized over 150 tickets after collaborating with stakeholders to create product roadmaps, OKRs, PRDs & technical documentation.

# Mobile Engineer Intern at Carfax Canada, Waterloo ☐

September 2019 — December 2019

- Prototyped an iOS app in Swift that provided real-time & historic insights about a user's car & driving habits.
- Initiated & implemented key features such as Distracted Driving, Live Maps,
   Service Records, Trip History & Rewards by leveraging several APIs.
- Improved application load times by 80% leveraging Firebase & Core Data to overhaul user data management.
- Other technologies involved: Core Location, Core Motion, Google Maps SDK, Spotify SDK, Alamofire, Heroku & InVision

#### Software Developer Intern at Nielsen, Markham

January 2019 — April 2019

• Eliminated manual labor by developing an application in python to recognize products in consumer flyers using **Selenium**, **OpenCV**, **OCR & machine learning**.

## Web Developer Intern at City of Toronto, Toronto

May 2018 — August 2018

 Increased efficiency by 60% after programming a web-based ticketing system for internal forms with custom validations and email reminders using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL & PowerShell.

#### **Details**

Location: Toronto, Canada Phone: 201-381-8056

Email: ganan.jobs@gmail.com

### Links

ganans.ca
linkedin.com/in/sganan

# **Technologies**

Jira, Confluence,
Figma, Miro,
Pendo, Datadog,
Postman, Insomnia,
Firebase, Git,
SQL, MySQL,
Swift, XCode,
JavaScript, Visual Studio,
Microsoft Office

## Competencies

Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, Wireframing, UX Mock-ups, Analytical Decisions, API Design, Product Vision, A/B Testing, Technical Documentation, Designing for Accessibility

# **Projects**

#### Smart Gym (2021-2022) ☑

Awarded University of Waterloo's monetary prize for Best Device for Physical Exercise from 70 final year design projects. A mobile & hardware application to analyze exercise form, manage routines & address injury risks.

#### Food Recall (2021)

Developed an Android application to manage inventory of groceries & their expiry dates using a repository style architecture in lava.

## Volunteering

#### FIRST Robotics (2017-Present) □

Former president & founder of FRC Team 6632. Now mentor for high school students building gocart sized robots.